Well, I mean, obviously I love the the
physical nature, the the the winning the
winning culture that um the Lions has
been having, you know what I'm saying,
over the past few years and kind of
being familiar being up north. Um um
playing in Minnesota a little bit and
then, you know what I'm saying, being
able to come back up north, which I'm
very familiar with being up here was was
a big part of my decision. And then the
familiarity with the coaching staff, um
just being around those guys, being able
to meet them, and obviously having that
relationship with Shep um is was was a
big decision for me.
Corey,
>> hey DJ, welcome to Detroit. Um, we read
about you and saw that you had um dealt
with blood clots during the 2024 season
just how did that how was that what was
that experience like and um how did that
affect you know the way you prepare and
um train and with your workouts and
whatnot. Um, yeah. I mean, it was a it
was a tough experience just going
through, you know what I'm saying, the
injuries and the different setbacks that
came along with that and obviously the
blood clots, but you know what I'm
saying? That didn't kind of stop me. Um,
it kept me um going obviously, you know
what I'm saying? They just showed my
resilience and the blood clots were just
a part of the um just a part of the
process. You know what I'm saying? I had
those things, but it didn't stop me from
working out. I was able to work out, but
I couldn't sweat. So during my workouts,
I I lift a little bit and then if I feel
like I'm about to sweat, I go run in the
freezer, you know what I'm saying? Cool
off a little bit, then come back. This
all happened um when I was in Carolina
trying to get back on the field. So um
it was a lot that went into the process
of getting back on the field, but
eventually I was able to do get back out
there and and and make plays.
>> Tim,
>> hey DJ, welcome to Detroit.
Um, just curious
what how much you're looking forward to
playing with with a guy like like Aiden
Hutchinson. Just what what you know
about him and and what kind of a duo do
you guys think that you can be on the
edge?
>> Oh yeah, man. I'm excited. You know what
I'm saying? I watch a lot of his tape.
Um, and that guy's just he's relentless,
man. He does everything. You know what
I'm saying? He gets after the passer. He
makes plays in the run in the back
field. And you know what I'm saying? He
drops some coverage every now and then,
but not much. But I feel like my game is
kind of similar cuz I'm able to rush. Um
I'm very physical on the edge. Not many
people running that way. And then I'm
also be able to drop in coverage and
make plays. You know what I'm saying? I
make plays all over the field. Um picks,
touchdowns, all different type of
things. So I feel like we'll be able to
complement each other. You know what I'm
saying? Whichever way, you know what I'm
saying? Coach Shep wants us to.
>> Thanks,
>> Justin.
>> Hey DJ, can you just build up a little
bit on the uh the relationship with
Shep? I believe you guys went to the the
same high school. Um, you know, how far
does that relationship go back and and
you know, what's maybe the how it's
developed over the years?
>> Oh, yeah. You know what I'm saying? Shep
was, you know what I'm saying? Kind of
like almost a guy. You know what I'm
saying? When I was in high school,
everybody, we all looked up to him. We
didn't really know him much, but we all
looked up to him when he was in LSU and
obviously when he got to the league. But
our relationship has kind of grown over
the years. I got to know him a little
bit in when I was in Minnesota. We
talked a little bit before the games,
but not much. But when I took my visit a
couple days ago, I was able to really
get like a a good, you know what I'm
saying,
overview of just him and how he is and
the type of player he was and being able
to build that relationship. We our
parents grew up like a mile away from
each other, which is crazy. Um, and
obviously same high school, but just
having that relationship with him and
familiarity with him was was big in my
decision.
>> And and I want to build a little bit
more on the the Aiden uh conversation as
well. um when you are playing opposite
an elite guy like that, the the
attention he commands, can you can you
just explain a little bit on like what
kind of opportunities that creates for
for you on the opposite side?
>> Oh yeah, it creates a lot opportunities.
Um just the elite pass rusher and elite
playmaker he is. It kind of gets him a
lot more of the attention as far as like
the chips and different things like
that. But you know what I'm saying?
Throughout my career, I've I've been
getting chipped as well. So, I feel like
um just what I bring, it'll allow me to
free him up. Obviously, he's going to
free me up, but it allow me to free him
up at times as well. So, I feel like
we'll compliment each other well.
>> And just one more for me. Uh you know,
went back and looked just a little bit
of your tape last year. You seem very
confident and comfortable in the
two-point stance. I'm just wondering um
what what's your history and you know,
rushing in different stances and and why
is the the two-point the right one for
you?
>> Um I mean, I I've done both. I did the
three-point a lot early in my career and
then later on in my career, um,
two-point, the two-point just allows me
to see a lot more. Um, just allow me to
see what's going on, kind of diagnose
what the offense is trying to do to me,
um, where they're trying to, uh, crack
me, crack block me, or chip me, just see
different things. Um, allows me to to
use my just use my mind and be able to
see what's what's going to happen before
it happens. But obviously, I'm going to
implement getting back in that
three-point stance, which is going to
allow me to have a little bit more
burst. You know what I'm saying? Getting
off getting off the rock. Um, so being
able to do both this year, uh, will be
big for me.
>> Appreciate it, DJ. Welcome to Detroit.
>> Back to Nolan.
>> Uh, you might not have faced him in in
practice too much or anything like that,
but obviously Lions also signed Kade
Maze's free agency period. Just curious
what you can tell us about him as a
player and a and a person.
>> Oh, man. Kade's a dog, man. I've been
familiar with Kade um since he was in
high school. My little brother um and
him kind of came up together uh going to
the Under Armour All-American camps and
different things like that. Um, so I've
been familiar with Kade a lot when he
was at Georgia and obviously Tennessee.
But K's a dog. Also was a great guy on
off the field. Um, we talked a lot after
I signed about, you know what I'm
saying, just how excited we were being
in Detroit and being able to, you know
what I'm saying, get up here and really
showcase our abilities. But no, K is a
good dude and I'm excited for him.
>> And then you guys obviously made the the
playoff appearance with Carolina last
year, revitalized season for that
franchise. Just how cool of an
experience was it to to be able to to um
reach the playoffs and and how motivated
are you to get back with this team? Oh
yeah. Oh no, it was really cool cuz you
know what I'm saying? I I was able to
kind of see what it was before and just
what it takes to get, you know what I'm
saying, over that hump and get to the
playoffs. Obviously, you know what I'm
saying? That's that's just part of the
process. Obviously, Super Bowl is the
goal, but just being able to get over
that hump, kind of see the work that we
had to put in to get to where we were.
You know what I'm saying? Last year was
big, but obviously the goal is even
bigger this year being in Detroit.
>> Thank you,
>> Corey.
>> And DJ, um, we see you're here on a
one-year deal. Sometimes people look at
it as a proven deal or can look as an
opportunity. Like what does success look
like for you when the season ends here
in Detroit?
>> Um really just just making plays, you
know what I'm saying? Being the best
defender that I can be for this team. Uh
obviously helping us propel and get to
that Super Bowl. You know what I'm
saying? We're really close. We got the
guys to do that. Um so just getting to
that bowl, man. That's that's the
biggest thing for me. And being able to
do whatever coach Shep and and the guys
need me to do on the field.
>> All right, let's go. Last one. Riner.
>> Uh, yeah. I DJ, did did they kind of
talk to you about what kind of role they
envision for you? Like what and what
responsibilities they really want you to
kind of like focus in on uh going
forward with with the team?
>> Nah, we didn't really get too in depth
um as far as what I'll be doing exactly,
you know what I'm saying, on the
defensive line and within the scheme.
But, you know what I'm saying? They
obviously told me that they'll allow me
to be able to use my versatility um
within within the defense. So, I'm
excited about that. And you know what
I'm saying? I'm willing to do whatever
it takes to win.
>> And can you describe, I guess, just, you
know, your your play, I guess, in
previous places as far as, you know,
all-encompassing what you did. I mean,
you were on the field, I guess, quite a
bit. They didn't have to take you off,
you know, and rund downs and such. I
mean, so I mean, how do you in how do
you view yourself as a as an edge
player? Uh, do you I mean, pass rushing,
run defense, what's your what's your
what do you think are your strengths,
weaknesses, whatever?
>> Um, I I feel like I can do it all. You
know what I'm saying? I've made plays in
every phase of the game. I've set the
edge hard. Um, I've gotten to the
quarterback and, you know what I'm
saying? I've dropped in coverage, got
interceptions, different things like
that. So, I feel like I can bring a lot
to the defense. Obviously, you know what
I'm and I got banged up the I've been
banged up the last couple years dealing
with the quad and all that, but this
year was my first offseason being able
to train and not rehab. So, being able
to get stronger, get better, get faster,
um it's going to allow me to have a a
much better year this year. So, I'm
excited to get back on the